Noah Tonnesen

♥ Montréal, QC

• ntonnes.github.io/

in noah-tonnesen

ntonnes

Summary .

Web developer and database specialist with 4 years of experience designing, deploying, and maintaining efficient, user-centered applications. Seeking a role as developer on a multidisciplinary team creating innovative solutions that support research, education, and institutional growth.

Key Skills _____

Languages: HTML/CSS, PHP, Python, Java, OCaml, SQL, C/C++ Tools: IBM DB2, Oracle APEX, Git, REST, Excel, React, Node.js

Interpersonal: Project Management, Public Presentation, Cross-Functional Collaboration, Technical Writing

Education

Gr.Dip. Concordia University, Computer Science

2024 - Present

- GPA: 4.0/4.0 (in progress)
- Advanced Coursework: Discrete Structures & Formal Languages, Technical Writing & Reseach Methods, Tools & Techniques for Software Engineers
- **B.Sc.** McGill University, Anatomy & Cell Biology, Computer Science

2020 - 2024

- GPA: 3.61/4.0
- Advanced Coursework: Database Systems, Computer Systems, Topics in Biotechnology, Programming Languages & Paradigms
- Community Outreach: McGill Student Emergency Response Team [3yrs], Montreal Chinese Hospital Volunteer [2yrs]

Work Experience _____

Maude Abbott Medical Museum, Web Developer and Archival Systems Specialist

Montréal, QC, CAN 2021 - Present

- · Led the migration of legacy artifact data into a modern, centralized database, reducing inconsistencies by 98% and ensuring data integrity with automated backup protocols.
- Designed and deployed an Oracle APEX application to manage 10.000+ digitized artifacts. improving accessibility and workflow efficiency for curatorial staff.
- · Maintained the museum's website built on a LAMP stack, improving overall engagement time by 45% for a global audience of 2,000 monthly visitors.
- Drove a 28% increase in organic search traffic to our website through targeted SEO enhancements such as meta tag optimization, content diversification, and improved mobile compatability.
- Oversaw a transformative project that introduced three high-traffic exhibits, archived over 1,000 new specimens, and resulted in a 3-fold increase in annual visitors.
- Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team to create interactive digital content for exhibits, significantly increasing the time visitors spent in the museum.

Hannaford, Produce Department Lead

- Led a team of 5 employees to ensure consistent product quality, presentation, and safety, contributing to a 6% improvement in customer satisfaction scores.
- Maintained and organized displays to meet Hannaford's merchandising standards, increasing product visibility and creating an intuitive shopping experience.
- Collaborated with department managers during inventory and product ordering, reducing waste and stockouts.

Bedford, NH, USA 2018 - 2021

Projects

Digital Marketplace March 2024

• Developed a shopping website simulator incorporating key functionalities such as user authentication, filtered product search, and shopping cart and order management.

• Tools Used: Java, IBM DB2, Maven, Bash, SQL

OChess January 2024

- Built a desktop chess interface in OCaml featuring standard chess rules, a user-friendly GUI, and "lazy" move evalutaion.
- Tools Used: OCaml, OUnit, SDL2, C

SLIK Expression Binner August 2022

- Developed a computer vision and image processing application for categorizing cellular growth in confocal microscopy images as cancerous or non-cancerous based on expression patterns of SLIK protein.
- Tools Used: Python, OpenCV, NumPy, Pandas, Fiji/ImageJ